it would be really interesting I think
if there was a piece of functionality
which was like take my Scrappy notes and
make it beautiful absolutely that like
100%
[Music]
that
all right we're rolling and today we
have a meal from kaida with us welcome
dude hello hello and we've also got the
Grinch apparently uh Joel tell show the
people your voice right now man okay so
a child coughed on me on an airplane and
uh it was funny because in the group
chat like I I I was like witnessed it
happen like I was like sitting there and
this child just like open mouth coughed
like right next to me and I was like in
the group I was like oh some kid just
coughed on me like GG and then like four
days later it's like it all hit me so
dude I saw that message too and I was
like a gosh Joel is being a germaphobe
or something like that and here we are
with the voice well all right Joel hang
in there man if you want to say
something you can say something or feel
free to like just message me on Discord
or something like that if you want me to
say something instead and spare the
listeners ears um but yeah we'll we'll
figure out my throat as well yeah well
that that's true that as well um but
we'll figure it out one way or another
um em man uh so I I've had the pleasure
of meeting you a couple times uh but
never in person just just visual or over
the uh the chat and um so and I'm
actually more familiar with uh kaido
through Ian yeah um because i' I've
worked with him at the live hacking
events before yeah um so why don't you
give me a little bit of an intro to you
and how you ended up in this crazy world
of writing uh an HTTP proxy for a very
you know specific set of customers yeah
that's a pretty crazy adventure um so
basically uh Yan is my my friend from
high school we we went kind of our
separate ways After High School you went
to a different University than me um so
I did a bunch of uh during University
and after that I did a bunch more on the
development side so infrastructure work
uh for AWS mainly a bit of gcp
I did development work also um and then
I was in between contracts like two
years and a half ago uh and then he he
just asked me basically hey I'm I'm
working on on this cool new projects do
you want to do you want to participate
on it like and I always wanted to like
start a company per se like I was doing
consulting but starting a business is
different from from just the service
work uh so I I jump on the idea and uh
here we are to wow dude okay so Ian just
says you know hey man you up you know
and says hey you want to start a company
and and it just and it just happened
like that huh yeah yeah and at some
point I'm going to share like the
screenshots of what it looked like and
I'm you would not believe it like oh my
gosh man that's crazy it was the light
team so I don't know oh my gosh oh light
themed the eyes ah um no but that's
that's really cool man that you jumped
on that opportunity and I know I know
just from talking to Ian um Ian is the
other co-founder of um kaido for those
of you that are not familiar with the
company um well you will be familiar
with the company by the end of this
episode so hang in there um but uh yeah
man you know Ian has has always said
it's been a pleasure working with you
and I'm glad he's got a partner in this
challenge because I you know I've been
talking with him a little bit and I've
seen y'all's company develop over the
past couple years and it's a lot of work
man there's a lot of Fe you know in the
beginning when we when we were all just
kind of at the live hacking events being
like man I really don't like burp you
know and we have this conversation at
the live hacking events a lot because
yeah um you're on your laptop right and
and when you're at home you know you've
got your desktop and the desktops are a
little bit more chunky and they can
handle it but when you're at the live
hacking event and you're like on the
verge of finding a cool bug or something
like that and then burp just kind of
craps out on you it's the worst so you
know we were always talking about you
know what it would look like to build
another another GTP proxy tool um but as
you guys are taking it on there are a
lot of features that that we've all sort
of taken for granted right definitely
yeah definitely I think like the basic
we got pretty fast but then after that
it's all the settings and All the Small
Things that one person uses but like not
everybody else that kind of piles up on
top of it so and so yeah yeah have you
guys let me ask this have you guys
um have you guys been how have you
balanced trying to get everyone able to
use the product for their basic needs
you know just basic HTP proxying versus
implementing some of these nice to haves
that we are used to using in burp or
other HTTP proxy tools yeah I think it
goes a lot with the the GitHub issues
we've relied a lot on that to to
determine which features is really
important we also have like obviously
business priorities and all that but we
do lean a lot on that uh based on like
up votes and how how much people talk
about them in general um so it's been
kind of our strategy it's not easy
because like there are some stuff that
we know people want for a long time like
plugins and we can come back to that uh
but they are harder also so we have to
balance also what how much we can ship
and we want to do a release almost every
month or something like that so to
respect that timeline we also have to
like choose pick and choose what we work
on no absolutely that makes sense yeah
and that's one of the things I you know
we've talked about kaido plenty of times
and and every every time we talk about
kaido on this podcast for some reason
somebody comes under the video and even
though it's in the description they say
and they add a comment hey how do you
spell kaido I can't find it it's c a i d
o everyone just I'm just gonna go ahead
and just put that out there right now so
c a doo Google it um it's an awesome
tool and one of the main things that
I've really appreciated about the past
couple years of using this tool is that
you guys have been um working off of
those GitHub issues right just like you
said so we have a of ability to
influence the development of the tool so
if you have some really great feature
that you would really like you can you
know if you and a bunch of other people
agree that this is a really great
feature you can get that implemented or
if a bug is happening it gets fixed very
quickly so I I've been I've benefited
firsthand from that that process so
thanks for thanks for sticking to that
we have some of our special users that
we like to please more you
know just it warms the heart it warms
the heart
um uh but yeah so I guess we sort of
jumped the gun cuz I got excited but
tell me a little bit about for those of
you that haven't heard of kaido you
should go back and listen to the other
episodes of critical thinking where we
talk about all the time it's a great
broadcast so oh thanks man um but give
give the give the listeners a quick
summary of what what the primary goals
of the software is and and what kaido is
in general so like you said it's a it's
a proxy so the goal is to intercept uh
tra HTP traffic between your browser and
and your targets um try to find
vulnerabilities like just give you the
most tool we can to like help you find
the reties and then replay the traffic
uh do some brute forcing if you need to
and then uh we are starting to like
integrate more and more tools as we go
along so just analyze the traffic and
all that we we or if you want to modify
stuff on the Fly we have the matchin
replace rule so we try to get as much uh
tool as you're used to uh from from uh
from burp Suite or zap into this uh this
new project and one of the features that
we have that is kind of unique is this
client server architecture where like
you don't need to run kaido on your
laptop can run out remotely that's
that's I think it's a it's a bit of an
education because people are not used to
to that to doing that tell the people
about that tell them how that you can
set that up so so kaido is is a server
and a clients it's completely separate
you can run them on the same machine but
it's a rust server so we made it run
like on almost every platform you can
imagine from raspberry pies to your VPS
in the cloud so you run this small CLI
on on the server and then you connect to
it via the your browser or we also have
a small desktop app that's quite a
lightweight but uh it's basically a web
view to to this server and then you
connect to that and then after that you
proxy your traffic through it it's it's
uh super easy to do and what I like
about this architecture is we're not
tied to to per license model for us it's
like you install kaido on any device you
want like it doesn't matter how many and
you just pay ones for that so wow yeah
that's awesome man and I love how that
also just very artfully solves the
problem and you guys are solving it in
multiple ways as you mentioned because
the server is actually coded in Rust
which is a far more efficient language
than than Java is for these sort of
processing tasks um so you've solved the
you know overhead problem in that way
but you've also solved it with this
client server architecture and I've I've
personally benefit benefited from this a
lot because I have a Chromebook and I
really like having this little
Chromebook around it's very light it's
really easy to use and I have a way to
you know run kaido on my server and then
connect it up to my Chromebook and proxy
the traffic from the Chromebook through
the through the kaido server and then
interact with the the kaido UI on the on
the um on the Chromebook itself and it
works it works great um and so that was
really I'm dude I just I love it so much
it just it just H it's amazing yeah
we've seen some pretty crazy stuff like
people run it on like Android devices
like tablets and stuff like that so
we've seen that people like one guy was
trying to set it up the other day on
like he had the iPad for the front end
and then he has his VPS he was like
camping or whatnot was doing hacking on
his iPad from his iPad yeah so jeez man
yeah before you like I've done that a
couple times and the ways that I've had
to do it was I'd have to connect you
know before kaido I'd have to just use
like team view or something like that to
connect back to my main computer and
then I'm like slowly dragging the cursor
around like no please um so that's
that's really cool man um yeah and it
it's it seems like it's been a great
great project so far yeah um so let me
ask you this
there's there's um you guys have
developed it to the point now where you
have a lot of the base features you've
got the you know the HTTP proxy in place
you guys uh have websocket history in
place you've got the match and replace
stuff um automate or like Intruder and
all that yeah yeah automate and um so
what what are the you know you mentioned
the client and server thing already but
let's give you let's give you four other
things you want to shout out um in this
app that people should be aware of as
far as features go that could help their
day-to-day testing life yeah well like
like uh we we uh we discussed that a bit
internally also like what we wanted to
to to discuss with people and and I
think the overall team is we want to
make people more efficient and and that
goes into many small sections of the app
so just from like changing projects like
changing I don't know if you use more
projects because of it but like I do
yeah I use a lot of projects yeah yeah
because it's just a drop down and you
just select it and boom it's there you
don't need to restart anything it's it's
in the app uh and we try to also keep
people more organized we have this
concept of Collections and we're going
to expand it more with notes related to
collection and all that so that's
another thing we we tried to like it was
a nightmare for just keeping your replay
collections or yeah tell tell me about
okay so the collections I I've got I've
got kaido open here um is that if I go
here and to replay and then I've got
okay I can add various thing and this
allows me to group my various sort of
logical entities of the HTTP request is
that correct exactly yeah that that's
the goal and what we found is like
people were like ah it's annoying you
have to like put it in a collection and
whatnot but at the end of the day like
on once you go back to your stuff it's
interesting because like it is more
organized and you can find stuff faster
than than you used to so that's our our
premise we Tred to to push gently push
our users to like be more organized and
I think we're going to add more features
like eventually with reporting and
that's the same philosophy we're going
to we're going to take in terms of like
keeping you organized as much as
possible so yeah no that's great any
tools that will help me along the way
with that I'm I'm very grateful for we
talk about it on the podcast all the
time but if you if you talk to all of
the top hackers um and you ask them hey
like what does your organization flow or
your notetaking flow look like well
they're they're all like well I've got
this scratch Pad next to my desk and
like sometimes I write down every third
letter of a request or something you
know it's like or like I've got like
notes.txt and then I just literally cat
everything into that you know like um
and so you know we're by Nature we're a
very it seems we're a very disorganized
Bunch um and so I me it goes part of the
creativity you need for like this kind
of word right so it's like usually like
I'm a bit like that also but uh yeah
it's a question of
keeping you organized like you need
tools you need strategies for that so I
think that's kind of our philosophy in
terms of yeah I remember I remember very
clearly the first time I found out that
you could rename burp tabs and I was
like oh this is amazing and and I think
they've implemented maybe I think you
guys actually implemented collections
first so maybe this was a response to to
that in burp but they've added you know
groups now and so um you know this this
is definitely where the industry is
moving and I think you guys made it took
a great step with that um and so I I
it's definitely uh takes a second to to
get used to um with the you know adding
and and that sort of thing but that
extra layer of organization will really
help I think in the long long definitely
and I think we're as we build more stuff
into it like that's going to be more
present as we add notes and and and
things like that uh yeah so so then you
can take notes specifically on
individual requests or individual
collections or what yeah that's the
that's one of the next goal for for next
year like we want to do the whole
reporting and and just not taking and
everything trying to to go further than
than what you currently have so um nice
bur is giving you a bit of pressure on
the notes like I've seen they they
released some stuff so it's going to
move up the timeline yeah I I think it
would also really be interesting um
because you guys have this assistant
functionality as well that utilizes um
chat GPT right yeah we already have that
yeah and so you know if I if I right
click on a request and and I let me see
if I do it from replay and I hit
assistant there's explain and there's
generated C surf uh PC it would be
really interesting I think if there was
a piece of functionality which was like
take my Scrappy notes and make it
beautiful absolutely that like 100% that
but also hey write a report surrounding
this HTTP request right and then maybe
you get to give like a little like two
sentence blob right on it that says okay
this is the primary request that is
vulnerable to idor and then you know the
llm just looks at the full request and
says okay this is probably what the and
maybe you could even outline like
template structures for reports and then
the llm would just build it all out I
think that would be amazing yeah that's
definitely in the in the work uh in our
our head at least so and I think it's
going to come like more next year where
we want to expand a lot the the
reporting the more also that is from you
to like an acur one like doing that
connection faster and everything like
that uh and then from them eventually I
also want to be on the other side as a
business owner I like to be on the other
side so they don't have like when you
submit a report it's it's super easy for
them to retest and if it's if it's with
Ka it's even faster or something like
that okay okay so you're thinking about
like creating some sort of ah that would
be super helpful because like maybe oh
dude I think I'm seeing the vision now
okay so like now I I have my you know my
my setup here in in kaido and I like
maybe I could generate or take a
collection and say you know okay there's
the specific flow of requests in the in
the collection right and and then I
export it maybe and the person on their
side just clicks a link and and they see
you know kaido in their browser for a
moment or something like that and it
walks them through the the flow of
that's kind of the idea yeah yeah yeah
dude okay what the heck I'm so hyped for
that that would that's going to be
amazing yeah yeah we have a whole lot of
those ideas it's just a matter of like
we three people I I mentioned like I
don't think you met Chris before it's
our third partner so he's he's part-time
on it uh right now so uh we're only
three people and we do our best we ship
a lot of stuff for three people but
we're still have our limit uh now Chris
I I I actually haven't heard you mention
Chris before is Chris a new partner or
has he been along from he's been there
since the beginning it's just that he
has another job also and uh he's working
on what kind of so Ian I know is doing
uh well why don't you tell me a little
bit about the division of Duties a
little B yeah yeah yeah so Ian is doing
all the front end so if you like the
front end that's entirely him like I
find that crazy that he he he went from
like a hacker his heart man bless his
freaking heart yeah yeah and and we
don't even have a designer so it's kind
of crazy because does all the design
also so uh I'm doing a lot of the the
backend so all the rust code I've taken
over a lot I sometimes ask the other
guys to jump on it uh for especially
like larger task we have a larger task
of like rewriting a bunch of like our
ingestion of of requests and all that so
that's going to take a lot of Manpower
and then Chris is kind of going over the
the back end and front end doing a
smarter task because he has less time so
we try to to balance the work and I do a
lot of of the administration of the
business as a general idea that's what I
was going to ask was like does that
normally fall to I mean and and you're
doing both you and Ian are doing this
fulltime right yeah yeah yeah okay and
so that a lot of that business stuff is
falling to you as well yeah yeah so I do
a lot of uh just Administration things
and then I'm happy also to to do
interviews and all that so yeah right
right and th we have you here dude
that's uh that's a lot man and I think a
lot of the a lot of the hackers you know
that are in this community I don't know
what it is but it seems like there is an
entrepreneurial itch in more of us than
not um so it's always cool to hear about
you know various companies that hackers
have started and that sort of thing um
so thanks for sharing some insight into
that um I've got a couple other things I
wanted to talk to you about the you know
with with with in kaido but actually I I
want to jump I want to jump I want to
scrap that for a second and just go
ahead have some personal beef that I
need to discuss with you dude where
where is where is the search bar man
where is the freaking search bar for
like searching everything yeah for
searching for searching requests and
stuff like that like so I I hit search
right yeah and and I'm I'm here and and
so I I've had this discussion with you
with you guys before right you know I uh
and and for those of you that are are
listening audio I'm sorry I'll try to
describe as much as I can but also we
will have uh my screen on on YouTube um
so check that out there if you if you're
able to so I go to search and I go to
filters applied yeah and then I'm able
to you know specify various filters here
um but I feel like like one of the core
things I do in burp Suite or any other
HTTP proxy is I I go up to the top
little menu up at the top left and I
click you know file or whatever it is
and then I I I click search right and
then it just pops down and there's like
a a little search bar that I can just
type whatever I want into a red jacks or
whatever and I can select okay I want to
search the response bodies or the
request bodies and that sort of thing
and I I feel like that has been has been
that sort of search bar like experience
has been missing from kaido for a little
while and I'm wondering if that's
because of because it's very difficult
to implement or because it hasn't been a
priority on the list talk to me about
why that is yeah yeah yeah no I agree
with that uh I think filters in general
are kind of an older the part of the
design like it was done more than a year
and a half ago now I think yeah we we
know it's due for for like a makeover we
want to our our objective is to make
something similar to Wi shark uh in
terms of like four power usage yeah so
like a small qu language we'll see how
much we can make it uh powerful but the
idea is like under the hood when you
look at the API because basically this
front end uses our own API so right uh
it's pretty powerful uh it's more
powerful than the UI currently exposes
so we we still have room for like
improving the UI and but we still want
to keep um a version that is like click
based just because some user like more
beginner users they they NE don't
necessarily like want to to learn the
the query language at first like using
so we want to keep both but also teach
you how to use the language like at the
same time so probably when you add stuff
visually it's going to generate the
string that you could have created so
that's kind of like the idea of where
we're going I don't know in terms of
timeline uh I know it's a big pain point
so uh yeah shut to the heart and no no
um no that's awesome man I can see the
vision I can see the vision and and I
think it's um to me for me personally
and and I use the um I use the you know
filter based search search system on a
regular basis and it works it just
causes a little bit bit of extra
friction to my it's also not fast enough
like I don't I'm not like and I want
people to be able to like save filters
so if it's t Bas it's super easy you
just copy and paste it somewhere um the
speed thing I the the speed thing I
haven't experienced too much of an issue
with you know like like when we hit
search and burp it's like you hit search
and then you go get a coffee and then
you know you come back and maybe it's
done you know I was thinking more in
terms of like how much time it takes for
like to to create a filter more than
like yeah yeah no no that definitely
takes some time but we can still get the
result that we we need to get um it does
work at this point which is which is
helpful um and I think that's my primary
yeah it's it's in like the topish of our
road map like I would say like uh right
now I'm doing the Upstream proxies uh so
that's going to be done for oh nice
ideally next next release uh that would
be that'd be awesome so let me ask a
little bit about that too because
there's a lot of features uh people need
and uh there's a lot of um you know and
like you said you're you're one guy or
maybe one and a half guys sometimes you
know when your when your people come
over and work on the rust stuff how do
you how are you feeling about the
decision to go with rust um because I
know I've talked to a couple people that
have written written software and rust
and they've said it's great I love it
but it takes a long ass time to develop
stuff so I how how are you feeling about
that I agree I agree with that statement
I think yes definitely it takes longer
to
build uh and just reason about trying to
find the right architecture where like
you're taking you have to think a lot
about the data ownership and how it
interacts and and all of that so that's
a bit more annoying
um I feel that the stability you gain
once it's written is is worth the time
if you can spend it like if you if if
you don't have the time initially it's
like ah it's annoying but once you've
written it it's stable like stuff we've
written like two and a half years ago we
never had problems with uh wow to this
day so it's like that's cool yeah and
when you break break something usually
the compilers help a lot more than other
languages I found uh that doesn't mean
you don't need test we have like a lot
of test in the backend sure um but still
helps a lot on on just like uh basic
mistakes that you would make so yeah so
I guess the rubber meets the road with
this
question would you do it again you know
in rust or would you or do you think
that this type of project lends itself
to a little bit more of a high-speed
development environment that you might
be able to get with go and not get as
you know the performance you know and
and sacrificing a little bit of the
performance trade-off yeah that's true
um I'm not sure exact I'm not sure it's
a hard question it's a we don't shy away
from the hard questions here
so and I'm not sure is a perfectly valid
answer um but uh you know I just wanted
to get your thoughts on it no that's
true you you tend to go faster with
golang I think for a long time I was
like uh oh man we should have done that
in goang but the more you I like the
language way better than goang it's a in
my opinion it's a way better design
language the the only thing is like the
async part that we use like if you've
used bit of rust you've seen a bit like
async rust is not as nice to use with uh
it's honestly some of the stuff I've
written and like or read from libraries
this is like the most difficult stuff
I've seen in programming languages like
honestly wow jeez man that's that's
intense because of the acing part that
is different so yeah that makes sense
all right well well thanks for being
honest with that I know I know that it's
uh it's a little bit it's a little bit
tricky and maybe the grass always seems
greener on on the other side you know
when
you're dealing with these asek garbage
and rust but on the other side I have
like zero uh zero like if I knew to go
to a CA Library I don't have any penalty
like a lot of stuff you gain from from
from from that so it's always a
trade-off it's everything in engineering
is I'm just going to give a shout out to
Donut as well right now who listens to
this podcast I know that is you know
donut if I said anything negative about
rust that I shouldn't have said I'm
sorry man please don't you know DM me
afterwards being like you bloody bloody
blah um no I think it's fair it's fair
yeah and it's it's definitely you know I
think I think it's a so from my very
uned uneducated perspective and
inexperienced perspective on this sort
of thing I think it that's you guys
played the long game with that you know
like in the long run once you get all of
the base features and all of your you
know and even o most of your nice to
haves out there and you're really just
working on like like listening to the
user voice and product Improvement you
know which is where you guys are
approaching now um I think that it will
it will really serve you serve you well
um it's just you you know I I I know
that it it it's painful to have have it
takes so much time to get some of the
stuff out that you've wanted to get out
quicker and we've talked about this off
air as well plenty of times before so
that's that's that's awesome man um so
all right now that I've I've solved that
Curiosity let me swing back around to
the to the the topic at hand um we've
talked a little bit about the client
server architecture the project
organization and stuff like that tell me
a little bit about workflows and what
kind of stuff I can do with workflows
yeah so workflows is a new idea we came
up with uh I'd say like four months five
months ago now uh and then the idea of
workflows is uh we want you to be able
to do almost everything you can do in
plugins right now but without having to
write code or like with just minimal
Scripts so that's kind of the idea
behind it uh we started with uh um
convert workflows which are similar to
um cyers Chef style um right that's kind
of yeah so in terms of like how we
thought about it it was similar to to
cyberchef for sure and then uh so I
don't know like people on the visual you
can see that it's a note based system so
you drag nodes into your canvas and then
you connect them and that creates like a
the equivalent of a script you have uh
ifel right now uh that where you can run
a bit of JavaScript to do your IFL
statement oh wow okay so let me oh okay
so that's in Branch right here yeah and
if I if I bring that on I'm sorry can
you yeah yeah it's a bit small for my
screen sorry I yeah to no you're good um
I'm not sure exactly but yeah okay so
this right here you can write write the
code to so you write the code a small
script and then depending on if it
returns a frost it's going to take a
different branch D this is this is
extremely Advanced you know you've got
like all these little uh you can and I I
love I think you guys hit the the nail
on the head with this um I guess knowing
your your audience because one of the
things I always tell to people that are
writing anything that is oriented
towards bug bounty hunters or hackers in
general is we don't trust you guys you
know like like you know if if you're
trying to write some piece of code you
know to like collect domains for me I'm
going to be like N I need to write that
myself because you know I'm going to do
something a little bit differently than
you're going to do it and and you know
the next person's going to do it a
little bit differently than me and
that's what makes this uniqueness that
in the hackers that that will give you
the wide uh you know varying results
that you get from hacker to hacker even
people that have similar experience
levels so something like this um giving
us the ability to customize a little bit
more um writing our own code into this
and having it on you know JavaScript and
output just sort of the Bare Essentials
that you need to control the workflow
exactly I love that yeah so we also have
a we added the last release the uh shell
node so you can like call programs on on
on your computer um oh sick so this is
like so th those are like for conversion
uh people have been abusing them a bit
we really do other stuff what have
people done with them well I don't know
like just H for example you can trigger
a a run from from another tool from some
stuff that is in the app so because so
basically that's why I say it's a bit of
an abuse but it's not yeah yeah yeah no
for sure okay so they there it's meant
for just allowing you to do stuff like
maybe there's like this white space in
this weird area that you can't get rid
of so you like you have to do like a b
an authentication where it's like a b 64
with I don't know a hash or something
like that stuff like that you you can do
pretty easily with convert and it was
meant that way I think uh we want to add
the next step of that is that we want to
add passive workflows where it's going
to react to events in the system and
then eventually active workflows where
it's more of a scanner type of things
where you you actively okay Tex or like
send requests and stuff like that what
we're looking at now is convert
workflows specifically designed to help
uh expedite your sort of Tex testing uh
process when you're working on something
and you're like all right every single
time I have to you know take this Json
blob format or like Minify it and then B
64 encode it then URL encode it then
stick it in the request and send it
right exactly and and this sort of
allows you to do set up that that once
and then you can kind of paste it in
it'll just take it from there and
produce that the next step is to have a
system like averter where you can put
brackets and then say this input I
always want you to convert it so that's
like the next logical step with the
convert workflows uh with integ into
other tools so this is so exciting man
cuz I can see the possibilities of like
how my testing is going to change so
much uh you know H and and I talk about
this a good bit um in Joel as well we've
kind of talked about his setup as well
but we both have our unique setups for
doing this sort of thing on the fly
without relying on tooling so I've got
I've got like a various set of uh key
Bindings that use uh what is this uh
espan espano right no it's not aens for
me it's Auto hotkey right so I have Auto
hotkey running in on Windows and I will
you know hit a certain hotkey and what
it'll do is it'll grab what's in my
clipboard and then it'll do something to
it and then save the result to the
clipboard right so you know if I need to
like do basic4 en coding or something
like that then I'll just grab it I'll
hit the key binding for Bas 64 and
coding and then it's Bas 64 in my in my
in my you know clipboard and Joel's got
the same thing except he's got a bunch
of like he's got a python library that
he's been building out for the past like
like 10 years that has just literally
every sort of thing is imaginable and
somehow in his genius brain he he
remembers the name of them every single
time I I do I like I write this the the
aliases all the time where I'm like oh
you know I should write an alias for
this and then I like write it and I
stick it in my bash profile or whatever
and then forget it exists and then I
forget it exists and then I do the exact
same thing next time so sometime somehow
he remembers it and um and so we've all
all the hackers have different solutions
for this but now it's this is something
built yeah and the shortcuts are coming
soon for for like executing
automatically without doing a right
click and everything we know like from
the way we work is we try to do an MVP
of every new idea we have and we put it
out there as fast as possible we try to
get feedback and then improve on it uh
the problem is sometimes we get to
another MVP and then we don't have a lot
of time to improving on it so that's
that's us problem but yeah otherwise uh
that's how we kind of work well you know
just just speaking as a as a member of
the community you know we we all know
that that this is a you know a work in
in progress and you guys have so many
features that are you know right where
they need to be uh and as these new
features come out you know we don't
expect them all to be perfect and we I
even personally like the the amount of
um ability to influence how these these
features actually work um via the
Discord and and that community so um for
any of you listening we'll do you know a
whole spiel about this at the end you
know go use our code or whatever but
really if you sign up for kaido at this
point and you are a part of this process
as as they're building out these
features from the beginning this product
is going to work a lot better for you in
the future when it it's becoming the
premier HTTP proxy um so definitely go
and get involved in the in the um you
know process now and you know get
acclimated to it as it's growing yeah
yeah yeah and yeah like you said the
best way is is uh to also participate in
the GitHub ISS and everything like that
the Discord we try to be as on as
possible I think we we I'm not sure how
much it's going to scale like if we
scale 10x the number of people in it not
sure it's going to we're going to need
some help yeah dude I I don't know how
you do it already man like running a
Discord and doing the business side and
writing the rust code and like man
that's a lot for three guys and wow yeah
that's that's crazy so you guys have
been putting in the work and we can
definitely see the results here um it's
it's really cool to see um so that that
covered most of the I think uh uh topics
that we we wanted to cover in you know
just highlighting some of the features
did you have anything else you wanted to
add in there I don't know a thing that
everybody talks to me about that is a
bit silly is The Intercept where he can
view all the
intercept I don't know if you're set up
for that oh my gosh dude okay so I I
it's already become like just all right
let me just hold on I I actually have my
um let me just go ahead and and
intercept it and I've actually got my uh
uh here tab up and I'll just go ahead
and look at this guys look at this
beautiful thing that has happened here
no no no longer do we have to click
forward forward forward forward forward
forward forward in order to to afford a
request we can just click on a random
request down the line and click forward
and it's sent and how beautiful is that
like I I have already like
this feature every time I use burp it
pains me you know like that it doesn't
have this feature you know and so this
is an amazing amazing thing that you've
got here small thing that makes a great
difference yeah man it makes a huge huge
difference and it allows for the testing
to be so much
more it's like you know when when you're
you feel like you're pressing forward
forward forward forward forward and then
you accidentally forward the thing you
wanted to modify or something like that
and it's like ah this is so annoying and
then especially if that has any reps to
it you know you got to go back and like
reset something it's the worst and and
so this really solves that problem and
one of my also we added the responses
like last uh oh check that out yeah so
have to end all the options on the top
but like yeah once you enable it uh top
left top left oh here we go options
intercept responses yeah dude check that
out so you can modify the response on
the way back as well I've been I've been
waiting for that that one was a big one
know for the for the time for the time
being I was just kind of using match and
replace to to to fix it but it's nice
that you have that now that's that's
amazing small improvement over time and
now we're almost set up to do the web
socket so that's going to be much easier
to do so wow man exciting stuff exciting
stuff in the kaido world um so let me
let me so we we discussed a lot of these
awesome features um let me let's talk a
little bit about the road map we've
talked a lot about the road map already
but um coming back to the road map um
in some dark corner of the kaido Discord
there were Whispers of a command pallet
I know I know when when do I get a
command pal H you have to bug Yan about
that I know it's not it's out of my hand
you know it's it's client side stuff
client side stuff but uh yeah I'd say
it's uh less of a priority we have a lot
of stuff in the the workflows for like
the end of the year that's like kind of
a we we kind of took a detour because
like side side note we were launching
soon a teams offering uh for if you are
like more in the Enterprise side or
business side so we are launching a team
offering uh so we take a we took a
detour of like a month that wasn't
planned uh to work on that uh because we
had a client asked for it uh so then
we're going back to to the the workflows
uh so that's coming but I don't know it
depends on the commment palets is I
don't know if Yan like sometimes he
pulls up like he has a bubble and he
codes that in like two days and he ships
it I'm like okay whatever guys let's
make that Ian's next project okay let's
let's go to the for any of you that love
a good command pallet and I know you're
out there let's head over to GitHub
let's go to the issues and up vote the
the of we're going to get it done like
okay awesome yeah dude I just I don't
know man there's something great about a
command pallet and haven't quite fully
replicated this in in Windows but um you
know I had this system a while back when
I on my laptop yeah um and it was
awesome and I could just I could press a
a key binding and a little box would pop
up and I forget the name of the
technology that I used for this but it
would pop up and you could program all
sorts of stuff to go in there and it
would have all your applications and
stuff and I just feel like that's what I
used for everything you know was like I
just hit that and and then also is uh
has that also uh works rocks it so um I
think yeah definitely but uh he's going
to Aid me for that but it's
okay all right sorry sorry Ian you know
who who mentioned it in the Discord who
knows I don't know uh uh but yeah
definitely high on my priority list um
another thing that I know um is
really well actually this one's a little
bit controversial okay so um I have in
my to ask you about the collaborator
functionality and as I was prepping for
this episode I was like hm collaborator
that is an interesting tool because it
it doesn't really seem like something
that should be integrated into an h2p
proxy um and and so on one hand I'm a
little bit in favor of not having that
feature around and forcing people to
like set up their own VPS and then get a
little bit more Dynamic access to to
something like this but for th for those
people that don't have I I rarely ever
use collaborator because I'm I'm mostly
using my my server for callbacks and
I've got a whole system that just dumps
it right into like a Discord web do you
use in direct ass or do you use no no
I've got a custom thing way way before
any of this stuff came out I had you
know my own system and being the old
hacker that I am you know I'm uh I'm you
know it's hard to make me you know
change my ways but uh so what what are
your thoughts on collaborator is that
something you guys have on your road map
in the future or are you planning on
leaving that out uh I I mean we're going
to have some version of it at some point
for sure it's just not on the like
shortterm road map at all um because
like you said it's like
people once like if you use an osted
Services it's you have to trust that the
OED service is doing not breing your
stuff right it's like it's always this
trust issue
we understand that so we need to create
something that is also self hostable and
we found like Interac exists so we're
like yeah maybe we can integrate with
that so I don't know I'm going to talk
to the project Discovery guys and we're
going to see what we can that would be
that would be really cool man um I think
HTTP call back is not necessary as much
I don't I don't think personally um
because I think most people that are
well this is very very like a personal
opinion thing but I I think you know
most people have access to that that do
you know web testing seriously have
access to a server where they can host
pcc's or try to write exploits and that
sort of thing right but um what most
people do not have access to is their
own DNS server that has a bunch of these
features right so if there was some sort
of infrastructure in place um that
allowed for DNS pingbacks and that sort
of thing that would be really helpful
DNS DNS I'm going to take note of that
because uh yeah DNS PS it's a pain to
set up I agree versus other uh other typ
of and it's not actually that much of a
pain for any of you that are that that
are like sitting out there thinking like
yeah that's a pain you know you you can
set it up very easily with DNS chef and
and some of the other stuff um you just
got to go and modify your DNS
configuration and it's good to go but
it's not
as it's not as easy to like hook into
like
like a a web service you know hook it up
into like a web hook that sends you like
a slack ping or a Discord ping or
something like that so um
definitely uh definitely check out DNS
Chef if you're interested in that um but
yeah if that makes it onto the road map
I definitely wouldn't complain but and I
also want to challenge the listeners to
get that stuff set up theirself because
as you when you do you'll start noticing
things that are a little bit different
that you may not be able to do with
collaborator and you know you'll be able
to set up redirects you'll be able to
automate some of your workflow um and
block people block the collaborator
domain also so like even if we do it
yeah likelihood of our domain being
blocked is very high even if we give you
like a subdomain for everything so uh
that's also the another case um I'd say
uh also like from a business perspective
for us to that's always a discussion we
had because we would like to offer like
stuff to to have that hosted for you and
then oh payloads and everything but from
a liability perspective it's very hard
to
take especially when you're talking
about sharing payloads and stuff like
that uh it's very legally gray yeah that
that that's a great point you know and
and like you said hackers are in general
a big fan of the decentralized approach
and and sometimes that is at the cost of
convenience and that's the price we pay
uh but um but at the same time like when
you go in the other side corpor World
they ask for that they have this check
their checklist so you kind of need to
offer some basic things to to get past
that checklist yeah and I imagine for
you guys you know just real talk here
you know it's hard to get a product off
the ground with just hackers being your
clientele you know you need to also
cater to other revenue streams and and
so um yeah I could definitely see why
that would be something that you guys
would integrate in the future yeah um
all right so I've got a couple more
places I can go but it looks like I'm
looking at the dock that you've got like
some questions for me it looks like yeah
well I I just threw up some questions
because I wanted to have your thoughts
on a bunch of stuff around a lot of the
the things we plan to do uh we talked a
bit about like the community like
integration with uh um bug Bounty
platforms and things like that so that's
that's kind of like we already touched a
bit about that question but in terms of
like reporting collaborations and
everything we are starting to think
about what we want to do in that space
like one of our goals as a as a business
is to eliminate PDF reports like that's
a stated goal in the company um so close
to the heart yeah so anything like how
do you collaborate with other people to
build your reports and and and and how
you see that in in in a tool like
yeah so so I guess for me when it comes
to reporting collaboration a lot of the
times when I'm collaborating with other
hackers you've kind of got this like
person that has you know you sometimes
you have 50/50 contribution but
sometimes it's like 6040 or like 7030
right and so one of the things that I
always volunteer to do to even it out if
I'm on the 30 side is I'll say hey man
why don't you just let me write the
report because it takes time and no one
really feels like doing it and that sort
of thing right um and I actually very
rarely see and you know you do see it
with like very mon you know monstrously
large reports where you know you'll
actually collab and be like in a Google
doc writing it at the same time sort of
Vibes um but most of the time I see I
see us writing separately so if you just
had something like uh like we talked
about before where um you know llm
assisted report writing that would be an
absolute GameChanger um and someplace to
store the report inside of kaido would
be really cool as well um and and then
you know we can write the the report
directly within kaido and we don't have
to worry about like okay uh and and to
hacker one and Bug Crow and integrity's
defense they've they've fixed the stuff
now where like it automatically saves
like every like two seconds that's great
you know but but I'm traumatized from my
my past of yeah yeah where where I wrote
like a whole report and then I like
clicked something and it deleted it all
and I'm like no um so I always try to do
that offline and then paste it into um
you know whatever whatever platform I'm
working with so if you had something
like that in kaido I think that would be
amazing yeah yeah you were thinking of
like how Okay do we make it
collaborative over an encryp like if we
do an end to end encrypted system where
like you each have their own report and
then we can do collaborative editing
over into an encryption that's something
where are considering and then seeing
like do we do we export in issues like
or do we export in PDFs and and and all
of that stuff so it's yeah that's that's
an interesting you know collaboration
there's a lot of a lot of stuff that
that could go into collaboration there
um personally I feel like I would be
more comfortable if the report stayed
local um you know and there even if
there wasn't you know even you know even
with ning encryption or whatever um you
know having the report just stay local
makes more sense to me because there's
no need for that to be anywhere else um
uh I guess if you are doing some
collaboration you could use a software
like what is it like hackmd doio or
something like that that's a great
software for writing also of course I'm
sure you know this but uh we live and
breathe and write uh markdown uh so
please please please use markdown as the
primary um thing none of those other
fancy HTML editors um um interesting
yeah yeah uh so yeah that's kind of
where I'm at with that and then as far
as collaboration features go I I don't
know do do you guys have any thoughts on
like actually collaborating like on the
HTTP requests or like on the actual
hacking part within kaido uh that's up
to debate uh we are planning to allow
people to connect to the same instance
at the same time like that's
coming um we still have a bunch of bugs
to fix uh for that but yeah like that'd
be really tricky to implement but maybe
maybe not yeah it's some it's not
perfect but it works because it's
similar to like you having two tabs and
then just having two different views
right so it's not that different there
are some actions that are a bit annoying
because it changes for the whole
application uh because it's not
segmented per User it's not like a per
per tenant thing or whatever so um I'd
say this is going to happen in terms of
reporting we are planning to use I think
it's going to be able to stay local
anyway but mostly allowing people to
collaborate over crdt or things like
that it's crdt is if people want to I
don't know it's a conflict free
replication data type something like
that I'm not sure exactly but the idea
is like you can be offline both of you
on each side and then you sync and then
it it resolves the conflict
automatically a bit like G does for for
code and things like that wow yeah but
but you can build a whole application on
on top of that system so uh that's kind
of what we're going for probably for
everything collaboration wise over the
network with two instances or multiple
inst and would that be over the Internet
or would that be over a local network or
what H that would be over the Internet
so that's kind of the idea is like you
can have a lot of instances and be
completely separate and then still share
some stuff and yeah so yeah but it's
good this would be a really interesting
feature you know cuzz I was thinking
like all right how do
we Aid collaboration without making it
too an interdependent on each other
right and one of the things that came to
mind was like man it would be really
cool if I could just right click on a
replay Tab and be like copy link to that
you know and it and it like takes the
replay tab encapsulates it in like you
know know some object and then you can
send it to your friend and they can open
it up in their kaido instance and now
they have that same request you know
that would be super amazing and I think
in general just uh more more access to
being able to very quickly share links
you know if you have I guess you'd have
to do like a you know time time bound
link share service or something like
that yeah you can do that even that's
something you guys would want to host I
don't I don't know if you want to even
host that but but uh we don't mind
hosting it if it's encrypted like if I
don't have if I can decrypt it for me
it's just a blob of binary data so I
don't really care I can host it it's not
no big deal right um so that's kind of
where we're going with that uh I don't
know if like reporting we had an idea of
a timeline at some point where you could
just like Drop things like that notes
and things like that and create just an
um versus like a markdown where like
it's text based so you kind of it's kind
of annoying for us to to insert custom
IM like custom objects because it's not
made for that so it's I'd say like
something like a notion would be easier
for us to implement because you can
create custom I don't know if you've
used notion in the past but I haven't
used notion very much so it's kind of
the idea of like boxes where box can be
an image can be anything basically they
can code you can encapsulate different
stuff and like text is in the box but
then it's a inside the the boxes it's
markdown let's say but you can mix and
match with other types of objects that
are not easily addressable in markdown
so huh that that that's interesting yeah
how would we want to because if the end
result needs to be marked down for comp
it Becky but I me to honest you only
have maybe not I mean you really only
have one major object you need to
integrate well no you requests and
responses you know like like you need to
have requests and responses so but
eventually we'll have like okay you have
multiple steps or you have a workflow
and all right with the whole like
workflow you sharing the the exploit
workflow yeah yeah true it gets tricky
man it gets tricky so that's why we have
to think a bit ahead like what we plan
to do and so some sometimes the
decisions we make they are not super
obvious for like right now what we offer
but we kind of have to think about like
six months or a year in advance where
we're going to be if we when we design a
new system yeah no that's tricky man I
would not be great at that uh it's
definitely a lot of work for you guys um
I I'm thinking as well you know okay so
let's say we were going to integrate
this into a report on a platform right
um we have the end result needs to be
marked down so when we we export it to
markdown or create the final output
maybe like your workflows become an
image wrapped in a link and then they
click the image and it opens up a kaido
workflow in their browser or something
like that but I'm not sure if the
platforms even really allow you to
that's kind of on usal yeah that's kind
of on us to negotiate something with
like acan and and and things like that
it's not impossible so to make them
change eventually like have a we can
Define standard for the industry that is
bit more mix of markdown and other stuff
so everything's possible it's just like
yeah yeah so but I mean hacker one and
and Bug crown and integrity they're all
they're all great and they are our
primary platforms but um you know we
also want to be able to use these this
markdown reports in lots of other areas
too so I'm thinking you know if there
was some way to be a like for example I
think actually you can do I don't know I
feel like I've seen it on some of the
platforms where you embed the data in a
basic C4 encoded blob inside your report
right and it's really ugly to look at
but it works just fine if you're if
you're you know looking at the at the
markdown view it's kind of ugly to look
at but if you look at the rendered view
it's it's it's fine so you could even do
something like that with a link wrapped
around that picture and that would sort
of create the nice brand
branding effect and smooth report effect
while still staying compatible with
Native definitely mark down export is is
needed no matter how what we do
basically so 100% man wow there's so
many so many ways that this could be
revolutionary man I'm thinking in my
head right now but my goal like long
longer term is eventually like if we get
rid of this markdown step and we have
like another format it is interesting
that companies on the other side can
also import in their system that's kind
of like you you cut down on the tech
space system and and you have a format
where it's more appropriate to well I I
guess the other thing is you know you
you you said a part of your company
mission statement is to delete you know
PDF reports but I mean you also have
that sort of compatibility issue when it
when it comes into dealing with some of
these bigger companies that need to
attach a report to like a jira ticket or
something yeah no for sure for sure it's
an ongoing problem but the problem also
on the Enterprise side is they don't
have a lot of good software to manage
their vulnerabilities uh and then that
understands like real like for me if
it's in Jiro it's a bit weird so it's
like they should have something more
specialized I don't know if we're going
to go in that direction they have that
they need to have that to give the
developers you know the developers need
to be integrated in jro but they should
have like uh something else on top of it
like that's step yeah maybe kaido uh
think
Enterprise vulnerability management
platform yeah yeah yeah that integrates
like that's kind of our idea but we'll
see how much we can develop and but it's
kind of the idea of like building this
whole ecosystem where you can have like
the hackers and the hackers are happy
and and the other side of the Enterprise
it's like they all happy because they
can manage their stuff that they receive
absolutely yeah man um I'm looking at
the I'm looking at the dock here I think
we covered pretty much everything um I
guess do you I imagine kaido is the
thing you want to shout out at the end
of the Pod yeah well I just wanted to do
also a small shot out because we made uh
the Kido po uh free for students so oh
nice uh I just wanted to mention it I
try to mention it every time I have the
chance uh so just there's like a small
procedure for for you to to apply for
that it's on our website so otherwise
yeah just look at what we're doing join
the community if you can get in the
Discord guys it's it's pretty nice yeah
we try to be there as much as possible
and and if you can you can support the
project also that's always appreciated
at the end of the day everybody needs to
eat so that's reality of it exactly so
so yeah including the uh you know ctbb
podcast host here so make sure you're
using your discount code ctbb podcast at
checkout um and getting yourself an
extra 10% off the uh annual license and
take food from a meal's pocket and put
it into my take money from a put it to
me no yeah we we have annual and monthly
so we're right now our our referral
program only works for annual so okay
gotcha very nice good to know man thank
you so much for coming on the Pod I'm
really looking forward to the future of
kaido and yeah I'll be using it on a
regular basis yeah happy to be here and
uh let's do something again at some
point in the future for sure man we're
definitely keeping an eye on you guys
all right that's the
pod